

24, Corso Duca degli Abruzzi, Turin, Italy 10129

🛮 (+39) 334 798-6923 | 🔀 m.bertrone@gmail.com | 🌴 mbertrone.github.io | 🖸 mbertrone | 🛅 bertrone

"Everyone thinks of changing the world, but no one thinks of changing himself" - Leo Tolstoy



Summary_

I'm research assistant at department of control and computer engineering of Politecnico di Torino, Italy, where I developed Polycube, an open source framework to provide fast, in-kernel, virtualized network functions. I love to code, but I also love to share ideas and feedback with my team, not only technical ones.

I'm working on network programmability, SDN and could computing, eXpress Data Path (XDP) and eBPF. I deal with distributed programming, APIs design, concurrency and performance optimization. I spent some time visiting and collaborating with tech companies in silicon valley, as part of my research work.

Work Experience _____

Polytechnic of Turin Turin, Italy

RESEARCH FELLOW & SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Sep. 2017 - PRESENT • Core developer of PolyCube: I am part of design and development process of the framework from the very beginning.

- Implemented virtual network services (bridge, router, nat, loadbalancer). Resolved technical challenges due to technology used.
- Managed to create a clone of iptables firewall, exploiting efficient algorithms and XDP optimizations, leading up to 10x performance gain.

Polytechnic of Turin Turin, Italy

RESEARCH SCHOLAR

• Developed a networking provider for OpenStack (iovisor-ovn). Increased visibility by publishing it under IOVisor community.

Huawei Technologies

Santa Clara, CA, U.S.A.

Jan. 2017 - Aug. 2017

• Development of PolyCube, as collaboration with Polytechnic of Turin.

May. 2018 - Jun. 2018

Nebbiolo Technologies, INC. (Start-up company)

Milpitas, CA, U.S.A. Feb. 2017 - May. 2017

• Design and deploy of a lightweight bridging networking solution, as substitute of Linux bridge.

PLUMgrid INC. (Acquired by VMware)

Santa Clara, CA, U.S.A.

Sep. 2016 - Jan. 2017

INTERN

• Developed networking modules, that can be interconnected to provide networking for OpenStack.

· Overcome language limitations, and achieved an efficient solution without modifying Linux kernel.

EISWORLD Turin, Italy

Mar. 2014 - May. 2014 SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

• Developed a network analysis and diagnostic tool for Fiat Chrysler Automobiles, used to debug and detect issues on dealers network.

Projects & Open Source _____

PolyCube https://polycube.network

POLYCUBE IS AN OPEN SOURCE FRAMEWORK TO BUILD FAST NETWORK FUNCTIONS WITH XDP AND EBPF

Jan. 2017 - PRESENT

2014 - 2016

- I'm core developer of Polycube, major contribution to design and implement the framework.
- · Created a framework for both users and developers. Users can deploy services and connect them together, developers can customize and implement optimized services using eBPF and XDP and the abstraction layer provided by the framework.

Skills

Programming C/C++, eBPF, Go, C#, JAVA, LaTeX

Tools Linux, Git Languages Italian, English

Education .

Polytechnic of Turin Turin, Italy

MASTER'S DEGREE, COMPUTER ENGINEERING, 110/110

Polytechnic of Turin Turin, Italy

BSC Degree, Computer Engineering, 110/110 2011 - 2014

MATTEO BERTRONE · RÉSUMÉ **DECEMBER 27, 2018**